Matei-Alexandru Gardus

- 27361 Quincy Ln, Temecula, CA, 92591, United States
- **(**310) 634-7520
- Storm_FireFox1#3515
- Storm_FireFox1
- StormFireFox1
- Storm_FireFox1
- stormhub.io



■ Profile

Focused Computer Science major (3.77 GPA) currently attending UC San Diego, with 5+ years of programming experience, and 2 years of professional experience. Aiming to use my knowledge of application development, development operations, advanced technology and instructional programming skills to make a good project manager for the Side-Projects team. Frequently praised as proactive by my peers.



Education

UC San Diego, Computer Science Undergraduate

2019/09 - present | La Jolla, CA

Currently in the first year, seeking to study Artificial Intelligence. 3.77 GPA. 4.0 GPA on all CSE-related courses.

"Tudor Vianu" National Computer Science High School,

2016/09 - 2019/06 | Bucharest, Romania

High School

Extensive study of computer science concepts, as well as extensive general education. Comprehensive studies of data structures, algorithms, databases, software development and Object-Oriented Programming.

While not accredited by UCSD, many of the courses taken at this high school cover knowledge that extends to select upper-division CS courses at UCSD.

"Cantemir Vodă" National High School, High School

2015/09 - 2016/06 | Bucharest, Romania

Former high school before transferring to the aforementioned high school. Studied basics and in Computer Science.



Courses

Web Technologies Course, Stanford Summer Session

2019/07 - 2019/08 | Palo Alto, CA

Summer camp of 3 weeks, where web development using Node.js Express was covered extensively. Culminated with the creation of BubbleChat, a match-making chat program. Won Best Backend prize and second place for Best Overall Web Technologies project.

Machine Learning, Coursera - Stanford University

2018/06 - 2018/08

Course taught by Andrew Ng, covers basic machine learning concepts. Obtained knowledge in elementary computer vision and machine learning algorithms.



CS Projects

Probleme-Info-11G, Co-Creator

2017/09 - 2019/06

GitHub repository with numerous exercises from multiple Romanian competitive programming websites, used as a wiki for lessons regarding complex algorithms and data structures. Helped improve instructional skills, as well as consolidate knowledge in the aforementioned concepts.

VianuEdu, Co-Creator 2017/10 - 2018/06

Educational software, capable of administering homework, as well as tests. Designed with scale and security in mind. Can support as many courses as required by school, and also maintains all grades in an easily accessible database. Project helped with acquiring significant experience in software development, as well as consolidating knowledge in MongoDB, Java and Go. Used by over 100 students.



Organisations

Bucharest Youth League, Technical Manager

2017/08 - 2019/02

Managed technical aspects of running the Bucharest Model NATO Conference with over 300 delegates, such as dealing with attendance lists and managing logistical aspects of conference. Provided valuable insights in talk topics at conference and implemented confidential distribution platform for delegate proposals.

Romanian Masters of Physics,

2017/09 - 2017/12 | Bucharest, Romania

Volunteer Manager & Introduction Speaker

Managed 40 volunteers working on manufacturing experiments for practical part of competition. Gained extensive leadership and organizational skills. Held introduction speech highlighting the many great aspects of "Tudor Vianu" National Computer Science High School.



Professional Experience

Digital Sky, Back-end Developer

2020/01 - present | Bucharest, Romania

Managed databases and client-oriented software for television and satellite broadcasting company. Migrated multiple self-hosted instances of e-mail servers. Currently working on overhauling DNS servers backing the company.

Undisclosed, Machine Learning and DevOps Consultant

2018/10 - 2019/04 | Bucharest, Romania

Implemented machine learning algorithms to streamline match-making aspects for internal database items. Will disclose details on question-by-question basis.

Realitatea TV, Television Broadcasting Intern

2018/07 - 2018/08 | Bucharest, Romania

Supervised and assigned duties to engineers engaged in technical control and production of radio and television programs. Directed camera and video staff concerning shading and composition. Managed the technical aspects and the program details of various prime-time live broadcasts of high-profile events.



Languages

Romanian

English

Native Language

Cambridge C2, TOEFL 119/120

German

Romanian Education Programme